HIRANJE

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT CAPGEMINI

https://jainchiranjeev.dev

cjain 252@gmail.com



ABOUT ME

Passionate Software Developer with experience in Core Java, native Android Development and C#.NET. Experienced in development and implementation of Client-Server applications in Java and Android. Various modules of android application development and several projects to back that up. Java and Android Development are my forte.



CONTACT

Address:

Airoli, Navi Mumbai

Mobile:

+91 756 770 2491

Fmail:

cjain252@gmail.com

Skype: cjain252



SKILLS

JAVA PROGRAMMING ANDROID APP DEVELOPMENT MYSQL, SQL SERVER

C#.NET

HTML/CSS/JS

AMAZON AWS RDS, S3, BEANSTALK

WEB DEVELOPMENT

GIT

ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR & XD

AND MORE



EXPERIENCES

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT CAPGEMINI INDIA

OCT. 2017 - PRESENT

- Worked with a team for the creation of an in-house code coverage tool with Java, SpringBoot, MySQL and Angular. Also worked on CORS issue on API endpoints.
- Built a Find and Reserve Utility for internal teams working on Data using SQL Server, SpringBoot & some basic Angular for front-end.
- Worked with various teams on and offshore for upgrading a major application built on .NET, SQL Server and hosted on IIS Server.

ANDROID DEVELOPER

FREELANCER

JUL. 2016 - PRESENT

- Involved in full lifecycle of the projects including design, development and deployment to build intuitive, robust and pixel-perfect applications while also working on back-end systems.
- Worked with various architecture components like Jetpack/AndroidX, Room, ViewModel & LiveData, Services, BroadcastListeners, SQLite Databases and more
- Worked on various tools for responsive functionalities like Google Cloud Messaging, Firebase Auth, Realtime Database, Analytics & Ads, Picasso. Glide. MPAndroidCharts, ButterKnife and more.
- Experienced with AWS for hosting backend systems as well as databases on S3, Beanstalk and RDS.

All the projects use Git for version control and collaboration with other developers.



EDUCATION

LDRP-ITR, GANDHINAGAR BE (COMPUTER ENGINEERING)

2013 - 2017

I finished my Computer Engineering degree with a CGPA of 8.59. My subjects of interest were Java and Android development.

Mini Project: NFC Driven Door Locks

Final Year Project: Pedestrian Detection using OpenCV



CERTIFICATIONS

Oracle Certified Associate Java Programmer (1Z0-808)

2016

Microsoft Certified C# Developer (70-486)

2018